"sekkaku hareta kara" tte iiwake o hitotsu houri nage
"The sun's finally out", I shout out an excuse
gareeji kara ikioi makase tobidashita
and fly out of the garage eagerly
mokutekichi wa minami e
I head south, pedaling hard toward the ocean
fumikonde iku pedaru wa umi no hou
chizu nante minai kimerareta you na ruuto wa iya
I don't want to take a route that
I already know without looking at a map
dareka no wadachi wa ashi ga torarete komaru
Following someone else's well-worn path
will only slow me down
isshinfuran ni egaku icchokusen rain wa
The straight line drawn with my heart and soul
boku ni shika mirenai panorama e tsuzuku
continues on toward a panorama that only I can see
konma ni-byou no mirai e ima o kirihiraite ike!
Unlock the present into a 0.2 second future!
tonikaku koge
Pedal until the end
Itachi's Story – Light and Darkness:
Partner
Over there?
Yeah.
The "Akatsuki"?
Don't know and don't care.
Now get lost! You're keeping me
from my "art appreciation" time.
(ヒルコ)あそこか。
(イタチ)そうだ。
And I have to take this brat on
as my partner?
(デイダラ)暁だ？
知るか そんなもん！
Sure, he's full of energy,
オイラのアート鑑賞を
邪魔するんじゃねえ。
but he seems like
the type to die young.
(ヒルコ)こんなガキを俺の連れに
しなきゃなんねえのか…。
It's our leader's orders...
His talent will be very useful.
威勢はいいが
コイツは早死にするタイプだぜ。
How do you know about my talent?
Just who the hell are you anyway?
(イタチ)リーダーの命令だ。
コイツの能力は役に立つ。
We know you're aiding
anti-government factions
of neighboring nations with bombings...
オイラの能力を知ってんのか？
You're a Rogue Ninja,
but what is your purpose?
お前ら いったい…。
(鬼鮫)近隣諸国で
反国家分子どもに加担して→
Purpose? I don't need a purpose!
爆破テロを起こしているのは
あなたですね？
I take commissions to
cause explosions... using my art.
抜け忍のあなたが
何の目的で そんなことを？
(デイダラ)目的？
そんなもん ありゃしねえよ。
He's annoying...
Is he done?
オイラは 依頼を受けて
爆発を起こすだけだ。
Who knows...?
オイラの作品でな。 うん。
It doesn't matter.
I'll do it.
ウザいな。
(鬼鮫)終わりですか？
さあな。
もういい。 俺が やろう。
Let me make it clear,
I won't stop in my pursuit of art!
Do as you please.
But now that you're a part
of the Akatsuki,
言っとくが オイラは
芸術の追求は やめねえからな。
I expect you to fulfill your missions.
(ペイン)好きにしろ。 だが…。
暁に入った以上
任務には従ってもらう。
BLUE
All right, all right, I got it.
うん？
But...
you over there!
I'll never get caught up
in your genjutsu again, hmm!
Now that you're one of us,
I doubt that I'll have to
use my genjutsu on you.
わかった わかった。
だけどな…。
そこのお前！
I don't mind giving you
a taste of my art.
二度と お前の幻術には
かかんねえからな！ うん。
Leave it at that.
仲間になった以上 お前に
幻術をかけることもないだろう。
Sasori!
Partner with Deidara
and go kill Orochimaru.
オイラは お前に芸術を
味わわせてやってもいいんだぜ？
About time.
それくらいにしておけ。
(ペイン)サソリ。
Who is this Orochimaru?
I'll tell you on the way.
デイダラと組んで
大蛇丸を殺しにいけ。
Orochimaru has escaped
into the Land of Wind.
ようやくか。
Beyond that, I don't know.
誰だよ？ その大蛇丸ってヤツは。
That's all I need to know.
道々 教えてやる。
Let's go.
(小南)大蛇丸たちは
風の国へ逃げ込んだわ。
You Akatsuki sure like
to order guys around...
その先は よくわからない。
Hey, hurry up.
それだけわかれば十分だ。 行くぞ。
I know!
Itachi and Kisame,
go to the Hidden Grass Village.
んっ！
人使いが荒いな 暁ってのは！
(ヒルコ)おい 早くしろ。
What about my partner?
わかったよ。
Wait just a while longer.
イタチと鬼鮫は
草隠れに行ってもらう。
I've ordered Kabuto to keep me
updated through several ways.
(角都)俺の相棒は？
もうしばらく待て。
If they're headed to
the Land of Wind, this is the spot...
(ヒルコ)カブトには
いくつかのやり方で→
俺に情報を伝えるように
命じてある。
風の国に向かったのなら ここだ。
The Great Sand Dune of the East...
ん？
I see...
That's one place the guys
from the Village won't go near.
Is that where you're from, my man?
I don't want to talk about it.
東の大砂丘…。
Anyway, that location
works out perfectly.
なるほど あそこなら
里のヤツらも そうそう行かねえな。
旦那のふるさとか？ そこは。
その言い方は やめろ。
That's his hideout.
だが あそこなら好都合だ。
I'll blow the whole thing up
with my art, hmm!
We don't even know if
he's there or not.
あれがヤツのアジトだ。
オイラの芸術で
丸ごと爆発してやるよ。
Sand Snakes!
今 アイツがいるかどうかも
わからねえんだぞ。
It's useless...
んっ！
They know we're here.
Are you serious?
Let's go.
砂蛇！
(ヒルコ)無駄だ！
えっ!?
すでに気づかれている。
マジかよ。
行くぞ。
I was expecting Itachi to
be the one who'd come...
So you're the ones the Akatsuki sent?
We're going to kill you
without hesitation, you traitor.
(大蛇丸)てっきり
イタチ君が来るかと思ってたけど→
Oh, do you really think you can?
You're the boy from the Hidden Stone...
あなたたちが
暁からの追手というわけね。
You used to be in
the Demolitions Unit, right?
Don't treat me like a kid!
(ヒルコ)遠慮なく ぶち殺してやるぜ
裏切り者野郎。
あら できるかしら？
そちらの坊やは
岩隠れの爆破部隊にいた子ね。
Keep watch from above and
make sure he doesn't get away.
オイラをガキ扱いすんじゃねえぞ！
What gives, my man?
Are you saying that you want
to capture him yourself?
Yeah, since you have
no grudges against him, right?
オメエは アイツが逃げねえように
空から見張ってろ。
なんだよ 旦那！
自分の手でやりたいってのか？
If you want back-up,
just call on me at any time, hmm!
ああ。
オメエはアイツに恨みはねえだろ？
I have the geographical
advantage here.
THREE
援護が欲しくなったら
いつでも言ってくれよ。 うん！
ここでは 俺に地の利がある。
So that's your work, my man?
You're aware of
the Third Kazekage's power, aren't you?
Yes...
My hobby is to collect things
that I find interesting,
あれが 旦那の作品か。
so I took a little bit.
三代目風影の力は
テメエも知ってるな。
THREE
ええ 私 いいと思ったものは
取り入れる主義だから→
少しいただいたのよ。
What the hell?
Huh?
What's that over there?
ん？ なんだと!?
あ？ あっちのは何だ？
Is that you, Sasori...?
You bastard, how dare
you do this to me!
What's that, you damn snake?
It‘s the Third Kazekage
that you killed.
I used a Forbidden Jutsu
to resurrect him.
サソリか。 キサマよくも この俺を…。
Things won't go the way
they did last time...
(ヒルコ)そいつは何だ？ 蛇野郎！
Enough of your resentful complaints...
(大蛇丸)あなたが殺した
三代目風影よ。
私が禁術を使って
蘇らせたの。
Now then...
今度は 前のようにはいかぬぞ。
With your Human Puppet...
恨み節は そこまで。
and my Forbidden Jutsu.
Let's see which is superior!
Damn you...
さて…。
あなたの その人傀儡と
私の禁術→
Iron Sand: Scattered Showers!
どちらが上かしらね？
テメエ！
砂鉄時雨！
Unlike the real thing,
うわっ うわ～！
the puppet stops working when
Iron Sand gets into it, right?
Don't lecture me about puppets!
傀儡は 砂が中に入ったら
動きが止まるんでしょう。
テメエが
傀儡の講釈垂れるんじゃねえ！
Unlike the real thing,
I've built in lots of hidden tricks
into the puppet.
It's your turn...
Not yet.
What?!
傀儡のほうにゃ
中に いろいろ仕込んでんだよ。
This is one form of immortality...
It doesn't die, even though
it's already dead.
次は テメエの番だぜ。
まだよ。
There's no way it can't die!
何だ？
これも１つの永遠の命。
死なないのよ 死んでるけど。
死なねえわけがあるか！
Heargh!
Well?! How do you like my art?!
喝！
どうだ オイラの芸術は！
Why doesn't it die?
After you two die, I'll resurrect you
both in the same way.
Although, what I really wanted...
なんで死なねえ？
あなたたちも死んだあと
同じように蘇らせてあげるわ。
was Itachi's body.
もっとも私が
本当に欲しかったのは→
My man!
イタチ君の体なんだけど。
Does that guy have a weakness?!
Resurrection isn't one of
the Third's abilities...
旦那 アイツに弱点ってないのか？
You are both going to become
my pawns forever.
復活するのは
三代目の能力じゃないんだ。 クッ！
Stop kidding around...
永遠に私の手駒になるのよ。
I... am the Third Kazekage...
I am not...
ふざけるな…。
your pawn!
俺は 三代目風影だぞ。
俺は… 駒じゃねえ。
Oh my...
I wonder if my jutsu wasn't complete?
Take this!
おやまぁ
術が完全でなかったのかしら？
Is he dead?!
食らいやがれ！
Don't run away!
やったか。
Heargh!
逃げんな！
Art is...!
... an explosion!
喝！
Hey, c'mon now...
芸術は 爆発だ！
We thoroughly searched
the mountain of rubble,
but we didn't find his corpse.
(ヒルコ)おいおい…。
So we can't say for sure
that we killed him.
If he's alive,
I swear I'll kill him myself.
(ヒルコ)瓦礫の山を
くまなく捜したが→
Besides, what was with
that ridiculous jutsu?!
野郎の死体は見つからなかった。
Do you know anything about it?
殺したとは言い切れねえ。
It's probably the Second Hokage's
Reanimation Jutsu.
(デイダラ)もし生きてたら
ぜってぇ オイラの手で殺してやる。
だいたい あのデタラメな術は何だ？
You bring the dead back to life,
and control them like a puppet.
(ペイン)何か知っているか？
You can't kill it even if you tried.
(イタチ)おそらく
二代目火影が開発した→
So you must use a Sealing Jutsu
or suppress their movement forcefully.
穢土転生の術だ。
死者を蘇らせ
自分の意のままに操る。
We just have to kill Orochimaru, right?
Even that won't stop a reanimated being...
殺そうにも殺せない。
だから封印術を使うか→
What's the supposed to mean?
力ずくで動きを
拘束するしかないだろう。
Be wary of Orochimaru from now on.
(デイダラ)大蛇丸を殺せばいいんだろ。
If he's alive,
he's bound to make another move.
(イタチ)それでも穢土転生体は
止まらないはずだ。
Ordinarily, no one could
survive that explosion, hmm.
何だよ そりゃあ。
(ペイン)今後 大蛇丸に関して
注意を払え。
No one who joins us is ordinary.
生きていれば
なんらかの動きがあるだろう。
Another immortal has appeared
out of the woodwork.
(デイダラ)普通 あの爆発で→
We have a request from
the Land of Steam.
死んでねえはずがないんだがな
うん。
A homicidal maniac
has appeared
(ヒルコ)ここに来るヤツは
皆 普通じゃねえからな。
and they want us to eliminate him.
Don't they have
their own Hidden Steam shinobi?
(小南)不死身ということでは
もう１人 現れたわ。
Apparently, they can't kill it.
(ペイン)湯の国からの依頼だ。
So this homicidal maniac
is immortal too?
殺人鬼が現れたので
退治してほしいそうだ。
Was he "reani-whatevered"
by Orochimaru too?
(角都)あそこにも湯隠れの忍が
いるだろうが。
I'm dispatching
a different team this time.
(小南)彼らでは殺せないそうなの。
(イタチ)その殺人鬼が
不死身というわけか。
(デイダラ)じゃあ ソイツも大蛇丸の
穢土なんとか とかか？
(ペイン)今回は編成をかえて
メンバーを派遣する。
You there...
Would you like to join
the Way of Jashin?
(飛段)そこのアンタ。
This wasn't for money or revenge.
ジャシン教に入らねえか？
This was out of
a deep desire to kill.
There are other ways
to quench blood thirst...
He had some other purpose.
(角都)金目当てでもなけりゃ
恨みでもない。
You really have
a way of irritating me.
単に殺したくて殺したな。
殺戮がしたいのなら
別のやり方もある。
And you... Did you come to
make sure I don't kill Itachi?
何か目的があってのことだろう。
やはり 俺をイラッとさせやがるな
テメエは。
There are no other
Sensory types besides me.
And...
The others certainly aren't
cut out to be decoys.
それで お前は
俺がイタチを殺さないように→
Decoys?
見張りに来たのか？
(小南)他に感知タイプがいないから。
それに 他のメンバーでは
とてもオトリにはなれないから。
All right then...
オトリ？
Hey, you over there.
Do you want to join
the Way of Jashin?
よっと！
Way of Jashin?
Yeah, the Way of Jashin...
What is that?
You can kill people and
you won't be punished.
よう そこのアンタ！
ジャシン教に入らねえか？
In fact, it just pleases
Lord Jashin even more.
ジャシン教？
そうだ ジャシン教だ。
I see...
どういうものなの？
What do you say?
Isn't that a wonderful teaching?
人を殺しても
なんら裁かれることはない。
Are you interested in joining?
So you're the homicidal maniac...
それどころか ジャシン様は更に
お喜びになるんだよ。
Homicidal maniac?
That's not it at all.
そう。
どうだ すばらしい教えだろう。
入る気になったか？
I'm just offering up prayers
to Lord Jashin.
やはり あなたが
連続殺人鬼というわけね。
Looks like I'll just have to
offer you up to Lord Jashin.
Well?
殺人鬼？ そりゃねえぜ。
He doesn't seem to be
a Reanimation.
俺は ジャシン様に
祈りを捧げてるだけだ。
Fine. I'll test him to see
how immortal he is.
お前も ジャシン様に
捧げるしかねえようだな。
Who are you guys,
dressed up all the same?
You in an orchestra or
band or something?
どう？
穢土転生ではないようだ。
Let's see... The gloomy one
over there plays bass...
なら どういう不死身か
俺が試してやる。
The girl does vocals and keyboards...
なんだ お前ら
そろいの服着て楽団か？
No, maybe that guy there
does vocals?
We're nothing like that.
音楽ユニットか？ そこの
うっとうしそうなのがベースで→
I think Lord Jashin would like
you guys as an offering.
姉ちゃんが ボーカル兼キーボード。
いや ボーカルはそっちの兄ちゃんか？
そんなんじゃねえ。
What's wrong?
Is running around all you can do?!
こりゃあ
ジャシン様も喜びそうな生贄だ。
Well, I won't let you get away!
(飛段)ハッハッハッ！
どうした 逃げてばっかりか？
逃がすかよ！
フッ。
What? Done so soon?
グホッ！
Ouch...
That hurt!
なんだよ もう終わりか。
Oh...
I'll punish you in the name of god!
痛え…。
痛えじゃねえかよ～！
ほお…。
神の裁きをくだしてやるぜ！
That's not gonna help you!
Looks like the rumors about
your immortality are true.
ぐっ…。
Okay, let's start the ritual.
もう いらねえんだよ！
不死身の噂は本当らしいな。
さあ 儀式の始まりだぜ。
Everything is ready!
Die...!
すべての準備は 整った。
One stab into the heart...
死ね～！
Damn you!
It feels so good...
うっ…。
心の臓をひと突きだ。
Glory be to Lord Jashin!
テッ テメエ！
きっ 気持いい。
ジャシン様に栄光を！
You bastard... You got some nerve...
ぐっ…。
Hey, hey... Why didn't you die?
うっ…。
I'll beat you to death!
No, you can't!
Did you notice anything?
He licked Kakuzu's blood
テメエ よくも やってくれたな。
and then mentioned something
about a ritual.
That's probably some jutsu too.
(飛段)おいおい
なんで 死なねえんだよ。
He passes on any damage he sustains
to the one whose blood he licks.
ぶち殺す。
できねえよ。
何か わかった？
However, that doesn't
explain his immortality.
ヤツは 角都の血を舐め
儀式と言ったが→
Can you separate them?
あれも 何らかの術だろう。
Weren't you going to eliminate him?
自分の受けたダメージを
血を舐めた相手にも与えるんだ。
Yeah.
だが 不死身のわけは わからない。
W-What?!
(小南)２人を分けてくれる？
(イタチ)退治するんじゃないのか？
(小南)ええ。
What's the big idea, Itachi?!
Seems they're recruiting him.
なっ なんだ!?
A guy like him?
Are you kidding me? I refuse!
(角都)イタチ 何の真似だ？
Whatever the Akatsuki is...
仲間に誘うそうだ。
I have a mission to spread
the Way of Jashin.
あんなヤツをか。
Then you should join the Akatsuki
for the sake of your mission too.
(飛段)冗談だろう。 断る。
暁だか何だか知らねえが→
What?
Assassinations, war, you name it,
俺には ジャシン教の布教という
使命がある。
the Akatsuki will do anything...
since we're a band of killers.
(小南)
あなたの その使命のためにも→
暁に入ったほうがいいわ。
なんだよ。
暁は 暗殺 戦争
何でもやる殺戮集団だから。
I plan to continue propagating
the Way of Jashin.
Do as you please.
THREE
Our two-man teams are in place.
ジャシン教の布教は これまでどおり
やらせてもらうぜ。
Go and execute your missions.
好きにしろ。
I didn't expect to be
partnered with you.
You took the words out of my mouth.
(ペイン)ツーマンセルも定まった。
それぞれに任務を遂行しろ。
Don't irritate me,
or I'll kill you.
Like I said. Just try it!
I don't want your heart.
(角都)
まさか お前が俺の相棒とはな。
それは こっちのセリフなんだよ。
俺をイラつかせるな。 殺すぞ。
(飛段)
だから 殺してみろってんだ。
(角都)お前の心臓は 欲しくない。
Art...
... is an explosion!
It's art!
I still don't get what
your art is about.
(デイダラ)芸術は…。
Soon, you'll understand the aesthetics
of something that's fleeting, hmm.
爆発だ～！
うん？ アートだ。
Hm? It's the leader.
オメエの芸術は
いまいち わかんねえ。
A shinobi village named
the Hidden Sound
(デイダラ)一瞬にして
儚く散る美学ってのに→
recently came into existence.
旦那も
そろそろ 目覚めるんだな。 うん。
It's possible that
Orochimaru is involved.
(ヒルコ)ん… リーダーだ。
ん？
That guy!
(ペイン)音隠れという忍の里が
最近 誕生した。
I want you two to
covertly check them out.
Since you guys specialize in sneaking
around behind the scenes.
この里の成り立ちに 大蛇丸が
関わっている可能性がある。
I'll find him!
And make him go boom!
あの野郎が！
The orders were to do it covertly.
《ペイン : お前たちで
密かに調査しろ》
ケッ 裏でコソコソやるのが
得意な野郎だからな。
いっちょ見せつけてやるか
ドカンとな！
密かにと言われたろうが。
There's been an incident
at the Hidden Leaf Village.
Orochimaru's behind it.
Orochimaru used shinobi from
the Hidden Sound and Hidden Sand
to wage war against the Leaf...
《ペイン : 木ノ葉隠れの里で
事件が起きた。
But he failed to completely
destroy the Leaf.
大蛇丸の仕業だ。
Serves him right!
大蛇丸は
音隠れと砂隠れの忍を使い→
The Third Hokage
was killed in battle.
Orochimaru withdrew,
but his whereabouts are unknown.
木ノ葉に 戦争を仕掛けたが
木ノ葉崩しには 失敗したようだ》
I'll send someone out
to investigate, but...
I'll go.
ヘッ ざまあねえや。
Then I'll leave this to you,
《ペイン : この戦争で
三代目火影が死んだ。
as well as the status
of the Leaf's Jinchuriki.
引いた大蛇丸だが
行方は わからない。
誰かに調査に行ってもらうが…》
It seems they
averted total destruction,
俺が行こう。
but they've sustained
massive damage.
《ペイン : では お前たちに任せる。
木ノ葉の人柱力の件もな》
That Village was at
the height of prosperity...
How tragic.
That was out of character.
(鬼鮫)とりあえず
壊滅は免れたものの→
So even you have feelings
for your birthplace, after all?
被害は 甚大のようですね。
No...
栄華を極めたあの里が…
哀れだな。
柄にもない。
Not at all.
故郷は やはり
未練がありますか？ あなたでも。
Sasuke... Are you safe?
いいや。
まるでないよ。
《サスケ…
お前は 無事でいるのか？》
kaze ga fui te iku
The wind is blowing
yoru o mata yorokete aruku
I stagger through the night
butsukatte koron de shippai bakkashite
Colliding, falling, and failing
make sou ni naru kedo
I'm always about to lose
warawaretatte ii yo kanarazu umaku iku sa
Go ahead and laugh, I'll figure out a way
gomen ne datte ieru
I'm even willing to say I'm sorry
nakitai nakitai nakitai kurai ni
Until we feel like crying and crying
kirei na tsuki no shita uta o utaou
Let's sing a song under the pretty moonlight
donna ni kuradanai sekai datte ii yo
It doesn't matter how awful the world is
setsunai setsunai rarabai kurai ni
Like a sad, sad lullaby
mune ga kurushikute mo hecchara na no sa
even if it hurts inside, it won't bother us
naki sou naki sou naki sou na hodo
Until we're about to cry and cry
yasashii uta datte arun dakara
There will always be a gentle song
It's been a while Sasuke.
Itachi Uchiha... I'm going to kill you!
Ah, the Sharingan.
Nevertheless, he's a lot like you.
Who is he?
He's my younger brother.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Truth"
Has your Sharingan awakened?